<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noah Peeters</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/</link><description>Recent content on Noah Peeters</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahpeeters.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple discrete fourier transformation in Swift</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/fourier-transformation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/fourier-transformation/</guid><description>Fourier transformation is a mathematical operation that can be used to decompose a signal into its frequency components. It is used in many fields, for example in signal processing, image processing, and in physics. It is also used in cryptography, for example in the RSA algorithm.
Discrete Fourier transformation (DFT) is a special case of the Fourier transformation. It is used to decompose a signal that is sampled at discrete points in time.</description></item><item><title>Imprint</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/imprint/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/imprint/</guid><description>Diensteanbieter Noah Peeters
Nübbeler Weg 53
24768 Rendsburg
Germany
KontaktmöglichkeitenE-Mail-Adresse: noah@noahpeeters.de
Telefon: +4917642987761
Journalistisch-redaktionelle AngeboteInhaltlich verantwortlich: Noah Peeters
Social Media und andere OnlinepräsenzenDieses Impressum gilt auch für die folgenden Social-Media-Präsenzen und Onlineprofile:
https://keybase.io/noahpeeters
https://troet.cafe/@nono
https://twitter.com/noah_peeters
https://www.linkedin.com/in/noahpeeters/
https://www.xing.com/profile/Noah_Peeters/
https://github.com/noahpeeters
https://stackoverflow.com/users/10961090/noah-peeters?tab=profile
Haftungs- und UrheberrechtshinweiseHaftungsausschluss: Die Inhalte dieses Onlineangebotes wurden sorgfältig und nach unserem aktuellen Kenntnisstand erstellt, dienen jedoch nur der Information und entfalten keine rechtlich bindende Wirkung, sofern es sich nicht um gesetzlich verpflichtende Informationen (z.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/privacy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/privacy/</guid><description>Einleitung Mit der folgenden Datenschutzerklärung möchten wir Sie darüber aufklären, welche Arten Ihrer personenbezogenen Daten (nachfolgend auch kurz als "Daten“ bezeichnet) wir zu welchen Zwecken und in welchem Umfang verarbeiten. Die Datenschutzerklärung gilt für alle von uns durchgeführten Verarbeitungen personenbezogener Daten, sowohl im Rahmen der Erbringung unserer Leistungen als auch insbesondere auf unseren Webseiten, in mobilen Applikationen sowie innerhalb externer Onlinepräsenzen, wie z.B. unserer Social-Media-Profile (nachfolgend zusammenfassend bezeichnet als "Onlineangebot“).</description></item><item><title>Website redesign</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/redesign/</guid><description>As I no longer was a fan of the old design of the website, I created my own, custom, and &amp;ndash; most importantly &amp;ndash; new design. Because I use git and GitHub to manage the source of my website, you can find the old code in the repository.
I also used this as a chance to cleanup the content a bit. For example, I removed the tag system because I didn&amp;rsquo;t really used it and had at most two entries per tag.</description></item><item><title>Reverse engineering an Electronicx battery protocol</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/electronicx-battery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/electronicx-battery/</guid><description>I recently bought a 100Ah LiFePO4 battery from electronicx. The battery has a built-in BLE (Bluetooth low energy) module so that one can install the app of the vendor to get some information like the voltage or the current load as well as some other information.
I was thinking of creating some kind of monitoring system based on an Arduino or Raspberry. For that, I first wanted to have a look at how the data is transmitted to the app so that I could reimplement this.</description></item><item><title>Is the iOS Shortcuts app Turing-complete?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/ios-shortcuts-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/ios-shortcuts-turing-machine/</guid><description>The short answer: Yes.
The Long Answer In this post, we will explore how to create a Turing machine in the iOS Shortcut app. The Shortcuts app is intended to define more or less complex workflows to simplify repetitive day-to-day tasks. The usual applications range from simple water loggers to more complete morning routines which inform the user about the weather and the upcoming appointments.
But we have a slightly different goal.</description></item><item><title>Nutzung abstrakter Datentypen zur Verbesserung der Codequalität</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/thesis/bs-applied-computer-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/thesis/bs-applied-computer-science/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analyse der Verwendung von Datentypen in Swift Projekten</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-6/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Setup Homebrew on Apple Silicon</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/homebrew-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/homebrew-setup/</guid><description>Homebrew is a popular package manager on macOS to install a variety of command line tools and desktop apps. This means, setting up homebrew correctly is crucial, as it has to make sure that both native ARM and emulated Intel tools are properly installed.
First of all, homebrew itself runs without any issues so far but will print a warning during usage. However, not all tools homebrew installs are compatible with the new architecture.</description></item><item><title>iOS Apps on Apple Silicon</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/run-any-ios-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/run-any-ios-app/</guid><description>The new Macs with an Apple Silicon chip can run most of the iOS apps which already exist run. However, some developers have disabled this for their apps. This might be useful for technical reasons if the app is not compatible, but most disabled iOS apps run flawlessly on macOS.
Using the steps below, these apps can still be installed on iOS.
Installation steps Install fswatch. This can be done using brew install fswatch when the package manager brew is installed.</description></item><item><title>How can a subscription based business model be extended with mobile app subscriptions?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-5/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comparison of package managers for iOS programming</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-4/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/contact/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 23:58:33 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/contact/</guid><description>Here you can contact me. To contact me anonymously, just leave the name and email empty. By using the contact form, you agree with my privacy policy.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/hello-world/</guid><description>I just created this website. The main goal is to present me and my projects on the internet.</description></item><item><title>Google Analytics for mobile apps shutdown: Analysis of the implication of switching to Google Firebase.</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wie kann CodePush für die Verbreitung von React Native Apps eingesetzt werden?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Wie können UI-Tests die Qualitätssicherung von iOS Applikation verbessern?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-transfer-paper-1/</guid><description>Transfer paper As part of my bachelors degree at the Nordakademie, I had to write six so-called &amp;ldquo;Transferleistungen&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Transfer Papers&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; about one in each semester. Each paper had to be about 10 pages long and had the goal to connect the theroy learned in the lectures with the practical experience from the partner company.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Software - Wie nehmen Endanwender Open Source Software wahr?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-open-source-software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/nak-open-source-software/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Zusammenfassung Oberstufe Physik</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/oberstufe-physik/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/publication/misc/oberstufe-physik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/cv/</guid><description>Data science student and iOS Developer from Germany. Currently working as an iOS Developer. Interested in sustainability.
Contact Mail: noah@noahpeeters.de
Phone: +49 176 42987761
Address:
Posthof
Nübbeler Weg 53
24768 Rendsburg
Education Primary School, Silberbergschule, August 2005 to July 2009 Abitur, Otto-Hahn-Gymnasium Geesthacht, August 2009 to June 2017 Semester Abroad, Riga Technical University, September 2019 to December 2019 B.S. in Applied Computer Science, Nordakademie Hochschule der Wirtschaft, October 2017 to March 2021 Gap study in Electrical Engineering and Information Technologies, Christian-Albrechts-Universität zu Kiel, April 2021 to September 2022 M.</description></item><item><title>Digital documents</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/digital-documents/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/digital-documents/</guid><description>When you receive a document by me with a digital document code, you can download the digital version by entering the code below. The code is usually a five character alphanumeric string and is located below a QR code.
Wenn Sie von mir ein Dokument mit einem digitalen Dokumentencode erhalten, können Sie durch das Eingeben des Codes die digitale Variante herunterladen. Der Code ist normalerweise ein fünfstelliger alphanumerischer Text und ist unter einem QR Code zu finden.</description></item><item><title>freenet FUNK</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/frenet-funk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/frenet-funk/</guid><description>freenet FUNK is an App I worked on for the freenet AG. It is a mobile phone contract management app for both iOS and Android. It allows users to change their data volume daily and allows booking unlimited data for a reasonable price of less than 1 EUR/day.
freenet FUNK logo</description></item><item><title>PyMathExpressions</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/pymathexpression/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/pymathexpression/</guid><description>During the time I experimented with python, I created a package to work with math expressions I &amp;ndash; creatively &amp;ndash; called PyMathExpressions. It is the only python package I&amp;rsquo;ve ever published.
At that time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about parsers or how to create them. So this project was a fun way to expore them.
An important disclaimer: I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend using this package in a projects.</description></item><item><title>Wobbly Tower</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/wobbly_tower/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/projects/programming/wobbly_tower/</guid><description>Wobbly Tower logo Wobbly Tower was my first iOS game project on the AppStore. The goal of the game is to stack tetrominos and build a tower.</description></item></channel></rss>