<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Noah Peeters</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Noah Peeters</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noahpeeters.de/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple discrete fourier transformation in Swift</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/fourier-transformation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/fourier-transformation/</guid><description>Fourier transformation is a mathematical operation that can be used to decompose a signal into its frequency components. It is used in many fields, for example in signal processing, image processing, and in physics. It is also used in cryptography, for example in the RSA algorithm.
Discrete Fourier transformation (DFT) is a special case of the Fourier transformation. It is used to decompose a signal that is sampled at discrete points in time.</description></item><item><title>Website redesign</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/redesign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/redesign/</guid><description>As I no longer was a fan of the old design of the website, I created my own, custom, and &amp;ndash; most importantly &amp;ndash; new design. Because I use git and GitHub to manage the source of my website, you can find the old code in the repository.
I also used this as a chance to cleanup the content a bit. For example, I removed the tag system because I didn&amp;rsquo;t really used it and had at most two entries per tag.</description></item><item><title>Reverse engineering an Electronicx battery protocol</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/electronicx-battery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/electronicx-battery/</guid><description>I recently bought a 100Ah LiFePO4 battery from electronicx. The battery has a built-in BLE (Bluetooth low energy) module so that one can install the app of the vendor to get some information like the voltage or the current load as well as some other information.
I was thinking of creating some kind of monitoring system based on an Arduino or Raspberry. For that, I first wanted to have a look at how the data is transmitted to the app so that I could reimplement this.</description></item><item><title>Is the iOS Shortcuts app Turing-complete?</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/ios-shortcuts-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/programming/ios-shortcuts-turing-machine/</guid><description>The short answer: Yes.
The Long Answer In this post, we will explore how to create a Turing machine in the iOS Shortcut app. The Shortcuts app is intended to define more or less complex workflows to simplify repetitive day-to-day tasks. The usual applications range from simple water loggers to more complete morning routines which inform the user about the weather and the upcoming appointments.
But we have a slightly different goal.</description></item><item><title>Setup Homebrew on Apple Silicon</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/homebrew-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/homebrew-setup/</guid><description>Homebrew is a popular package manager on macOS to install a variety of command line tools and desktop apps. This means, setting up homebrew correctly is crucial, as it has to make sure that both native ARM and emulated Intel tools are properly installed.
First of all, homebrew itself runs without any issues so far but will print a warning during usage. However, not all tools homebrew installs are compatible with the new architecture.</description></item><item><title>iOS Apps on Apple Silicon</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/run-any-ios-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/apple-silicon/run-any-ios-app/</guid><description>The new Macs with an Apple Silicon chip can run most of the iOS apps which already exist run. However, some developers have disabled this for their apps. This might be useful for technical reasons if the app is not compatible, but most disabled iOS apps run flawlessly on macOS.
Using the steps below, these apps can still be installed on iOS.
Installation steps Install fswatch. This can be done using brew install fswatch when the package manager brew is installed.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noahpeeters.de/posts/announcements/hello-world/</guid><description>I just created this website. The main goal is to present me and my projects on the internet.</description></item></channel></rss>